Off the boot of Ben Donaldson we are underway in pool seat, Australia and Fiji. That's a first touch for William Mata.
Hull House number 8 for Fiji.
A new halfback from Avorle sends it into the air, replacing Frank Lemani. It's nicely taken down by Carter Gordon on half way but hammering defence comes in Australia.
We'll get a chance to play though and play early.
The veteran hooker, James Slipper.
A little high up around the neck of Jordan Pizaya and he landed awkwardly. Playing under advantage here, Australia Pizaya.
He gets to get up, he's getting his boot back on I think the issue but just creeping up early.
Nothing too dangerous but did slip up, definitely a penalty.
Good little bit of intent here from Australia coming through the middle. The kick off was a good high hanging one.
And you can see just the arm around the neck there.
Well going for the corner, Ben Donaldson, man of the match in the opening game, Australia's opening game.
Kick superbly.
And that too is a pretty decent start for Eddie Jones and his coaching team.
See them, see what the frontspots.
Oh, the crowd loves to hear Eddie Jones, don't they?
Not the most popular bloke in San Detti in Australia.
From Velocini, bring down an ice line out ball and they'll peel away here with Angus Bell.
Driving hard, early pressure coming on Fiji's defensive line as Australia who made a fast start against Georgia look to do the same here.
Regathered.
What a regain control as Velocini peels away.
Varned high.
Result, oh eventually to the ground, another advantage for Australia, second highest shot.
Early discipline going against Fiji.
Well sometimes you've got to take a team on at their strength and Fiji's strength against Wales was certainly their forward, the top five in particular.
Controlled the ball, controlled possession, controlled field position as a result of that.
So far Australia picked and gone, they've carried up the middle, they've committed those big Fijian forwards into the breakdown, they've forced a couple of high tackles now.
Just that left arm wrapping around the head there, that's the problem.
The first hit was pretty decent actually from Josuo Triesova.
Shot at goal, good chance for Australia to get ahead right at the start and deservedly so.
As I said Ben Donaldson, 25 points in the opening match against Georgia, six from seven kicking, scored a couple of tries, heck of a World Cup debut.
This just his fifth test and a chance to put Australia on the board early.
An easy action and an easy strike for Ben Donaldson, kicks an early penalty to put Australia up three points to middle in the opening three minutes.
The party team Australia for the World Cup team, Ben Donaldson.
Experienced rugby player.
Fiji, 43 caps, played in another World Cup, he knows the game, he won't be too concerned about that first three that goes against them.
Tite Tela for Fiji, sends this one deep down to Valentini who's had a prominent start, he's so strong with goal in hand.
Oh Valentini.
Inside, hold in front, Australia.
And Carter Gordon, the young fly half will send this away.
Well it's a good start for Australia, doing the basics well, keeping it simple.
Just the catch one carry, strike back to the kicker.
Decent clearance, probably have wanted a little bit more on it but it's good enough to get them out of the red zone.
Clear and fix.
Matavisi with his first throw, finds Nassili Silla in the middle of the line out and Fiji able to peel away through books here.
Starting in number seven jersey, the versatile veteran Gordon shot up out of the line, it's the F4 Sarikita Vettar.
Sarikita Vettar with his first carry.
Fiji already crashing in Australia, putting some shots on early Karevi, that time it was.
The big Fiji in forwards lining up, one after the other.
Now they go through the hands and out the back to try and create some space wide.
Bounces kind, the bump is massive.
What a walling.
Nassili Silla again.
Tala again, a go wide early, standing out here by himself, Semit Rundradja.
Glicks the ball back in for Reyes-Alevu, who's claiming he was tackled off the ball by Carter Gordon.
He might have an argument.
Fiji's captain, the ball's gone into touch.
We've got timing's good, let's see.
We've got timing's good.
Massive physical already.
Oh, that's quite high as well, isn't it, Babatini?
It's always a brutal game when Fiji are involved.
Just a little bit of a
trying to smash it up.
Just get a little bit of physical dominance.
Maybe need to stop those big long skip passes to start.
Filiyami Matsu just had a little bit of treatment.
He's back in the line and away come Fiji.
And here's Noyatha Levu, the captain with her first rampaging up over the halfway line.
There's a good of volley just to have a little dart.
He's manhandled to the ground.
Noyatha Levu, captain.
Australia tried to shoot up quickly.
Again, they go wide forward.
Matu who stayed out roaming on this left-hand side.
Looked to get the arm free instead.
Just pumps the legs and peels off another few meters for good of volley to clear away.
Spinning out of one is, we saw it into the lineup.
This weekend for Fiji tipped on quickly.
Tangi Tangi Walu steps out of one, but it's gone forward.
But Australia, Fiji rather giving it some air early.
And doing it really well.
Just that final little pass going forward.
That's too long skip pass.
It's just allowed the defense to shift.
And since then they've just tried to keep the ball in the channels.
Beautiful ball.
There was a man on the outside as well.
They created the space well.
Just couldn't get that final pass in.
Thanks mate.
Yeah, we could just see that.
Tangi Tangi Walu was just that wide.
He had lots of space.
It was a difficult pass to get outside to him.
If he had taken that and if he had got the ball in his hands.
It would have been a different scenario.
So finally, it became defused by the Australians.
But good attacking prowess from the Fijians.
First scrum of the match.
Both teams excellent in this area in their opening matches.
And that is rock solid as well for Nick White to clear away.
Samu Karevi will batter it up and run over the first Fijian defender.
It's nice and quick for White again.
It's Richiano, late replacement into this match.
And then there's Martin Wills Skelton for Australia today.
This one coming down for run.
Nawanganitawasi though.
He's so good in the air. Couldn't quite handle it.
And it will be Fiji ball.
The knock on from Nawanganitawasi.
But first signs of that aerial prowess of this exciting young winger.
It's a great kick isn't it?
Nick White, what a great kick that is.
Into the traffic.
Perfectly waited.
Almost regathered.
It's going to be brutal isn't it?
I said before Karevi is a big man.
He carries it up strongly.
He's dominant ball in hand.
It's a real battle of the physical midfielders today.
Same on the ball.
Seconds.
Crows.
First scrum was a thing of beauty wasn't it?
And that's coming from a back line player.
Okay let's go again. Quick reset.
It was immovable.
Quickly fellas let's go. Thank you.
Daniela Tupul for Australia either.
James Slippert starting on the tight head side.
A rare thing for him to do despite his vast experience.
Crows.
Boins.
Set.
Use it.
Kurovoli needs to get it out of the net.
It starts to wheel around and they'll get it reset and continue with the feed.
Well they had a go didn't they the Fijians?
They got told to use it.
Trying to just get that little shove on and earn the penalty.
Yeah yeah mate.
Andrew Brace decided rather a reset.
Okay let's go quickly.
It's a great contest in the scrum isn't it?
The first one was rock solid.
The second one was a little bit of a struggle.
It's a great contest.
It's a great contest isn't it?
The first one was rock solid.
The second one almost rock solid.
Australia will be happy.
Quickly fellas please.
Eddie Jones earlier sorry Joel.
He just underlined the importance of the set pieces out there today.
Got to be really really stringent, very very strict and disciplined.
Because that's where they're going to win the ball.
Bear in mind James Slippert playing tight head for the third time in his career.
Set.
Say hi.
Brace go down.
Kurovoli has to use it and he does so for Teller.
Nyata Levu.
Andrade has come flying in off his one.
Here's Wainogolo looking to get around the outside of the edge.
Chop back and feel just about keeps his feet.
There's Fiji.
Oh forward big hard run.
And the ball and the retention is quick as well.
Good spot tackle made though this time by Australia.
Fiji this time though getting a penalty.
And oh upon himself he's called back as the penalty is played as it opens up for the halfback.
Well there's a part of me that thinks there's a bit of justice there because he did try and milk the penalty.
But throwing the pass into Ritchie Arnold who was lying on the floor.
Don't pass the ball into him on the floor okay.
Yeah that's just trying to milk it.
I think the whistle is probably a fair call to be honest.
Fall on the side.
Effective quick ball.
Good tackle.
And the ball from Fiji moved it wide nicely.
Just got their runners on the outside coming back in field.
Coming out pace over the game on real game line success.
It's interesting that Kurovoli is going to be doing the kidney out goal.
Tietetela kicked one from three against Wales and Frank Lomani another halfback added a couple.
So yes Kurovoli given the responsibility this one right in front 40 odd meters out.
Strikes it really well.
The distance is good.
Direction is excellent and Fiji are on the board with their first penalty.
And we're all squared three points each in the center team.
Well they certainly had some kicking issues against Wales.
That's a pretty decent start though from the scram off Simrani Kurovoli.
Decent stride as he kicked it he had a slight hesitation.
It curled in nicely.
Rear piece.
Australia send the restart deep down into Fiji territory fielded by Tietetela.
Returns favor.
Good chance for Australia to build again on the 10 meter line.
Carbon copy of the Australian exit wasn't it?
More.
Australia got it well controlled in the back through the captain Poriky.
What did the captain see today in just a 17th test.
Having a little peek it's nice and organized and they peeled off some great meters now for White to be able to clear off and try and get his back line going.
But no way through the defense of Tuisova.
White just scampering down that blindside just wrapped up by.
Australia hit the 22 and Gurnambetty plays half back.
He's Tom Hooper.
Again trying to find a little seam in that Fiji defense as Carter Gordon has absolutely bent in half.
The ball goes forward into touch and Fiji's defense stands rather firm.
He is just smudged on that blindside.
Australia hitting around the fringes and then going blind again.
That ball had gone it may well have been a little bit of a hit.
That ball had gone it may well have been a bit of space on the outside.
It needed to go.
That's got to hurt.
Wowzer.
Could feel that up here in the stadium.
Both of you.
No just both of you higher bind.
I did talk about plate tectonics earlier.
Look at his body position when he's going in for that tackle.
You know he's basically at 45 degrees so he's already in a perfect position to actually go in.
There was another player just outside but that hit just to bring down the fly off for Australia.
Carter Gordon absolutely perfect.
Well Australia will be really worried about this won't they?
Problems in the front row already.
Slipper now with a bit of fall in one of his ankles getting it strapped up.
He's had a foot tendon issue James Slipper in the build up to the tournament one that he sort of thought might
a couple of weeks back really stop him from playing so he just cannot afford to lose another front row.
I thought it was a good contest.
Okay happy fellows.
Happy.
Come on.
It is a beautiful occasion isn't it.
The crowd are just getting involved now.
It is just so special.
Boys.
13 minutes gone three points apiece.
A penalty by the side for Fiji and Australia.
Simeone Kurovoli.
We'll eventually dig this out in fact we're going to reset the scrums.
The first one was a thing of beauty you said Joel Stransky.
The proceeding haven't been quite so good.
The second one was pretty tough and pretty close and then the next two have just been a little bit messy.
And Henry Brace has been quite patient to be honest.
Some reps may well have put the arm up there against one or the other.
Alignments.
Strapping going on the knee it looks like a real men's match as well.
The last two scrums have been messy okay.
Come on.
It looks more like a one out lifting strapping than an actual problem with his leg.
Straight.
Good heights.
Crowds.
Boys.
Save all.
This time Kurovoli does get it away and Fiji look to spread and spread quickly.
And they've created space here for Simeone Rundradja to power up over half way.
Massive shot coming across.
Samu Kurovoli put the shoulder in and did it at risk for Kurovoli.
Up to the 10 metre line.
Fiji on attack reconceding the penalty.
There's excellent work in there.
Ben Donaldson coming up with it.
Beautiful little move there trying to free Rundradja up on the outside.
Clearly got back on side.
And took the hit.
Just a little bit of a protection of the ball.
Look at this ball in one hand the flying winger.
Oh smashed.
Yeah wonderful reaction from the bench the Australian bench of course just getting behind that little jackal.
Very important for Australia of course they've got to prove that they can work at the breakdown.
Rip that ball.
Pierre-Henri Boncart the French mall and coach has been working really hard on getting in there.
The speed of getting in and trying to jackal the ball make the turnover.
Pericchi has been good from the line out he continues to be so.
Carter Gordon now up to the line little switch of play for Valentini through the middle.
Trying to punch a hole instead.
He's lost the ball forward and it's hacked away awkwardly by the lock forward.
Narsila Silla will go back and play the knock on.
Fortunately because that had landed straight in the arms of Kurovici.
He'll be really happy to have heard the whistle blow that time around.
Great steal again.
Contact.
Brutal head down.
Valentini carrying it up strongly but doesn't hang on.
He is a cool common collective and he reminds me a little of Siya Khaleesi in some ways.
Just as the same charisma the same demeanor.
Just always looks in control always calm always leading.
Same again please.
Close.
Midfield scrum for the Fijians just slightly off center.
25 meters out from their own both and they've shown the willingness to run from deep early on.
Expect more of the same exactly trying to get wide early again to Wainegola with his elusive running style.
The offloads only found his opposite though.
His opponent Nick White.
Here's Naungane Kowasi he puts food to ball.
He's bounced back in the hands of the Australians bouncing around all over the place.
It was Tom Hooper who scooped it up.
So Australia looked at countering again through McWright.
That's a good charge.
Promising Australian forward trying to work down a short side.
Oh Karemi almost got rid of Tela.
Still there for Australia though and Nick Frost this time.
Making good meters with each carry and now White will turn around and try and find some open territory at the back.
And the kick's going to dribble dead.
Okay.
Kowasi fans chin in their palm of their hands not understanding the decision.
It was a bit of space to kick in here to be fair but I'm not sure Karebeti was ready to make the chase either which is important.
Last play down the bounce side and Karemi almost away.
He's big strong and powerful.
Seemed a little bit of space but there's no real chase from Karebeti and didn't get the bounce he needed.
Little unlucky with the bounce really.
Yeah when you're ready mate.
No I was just saying when you're ready.
He does have quite possibly the worst moustache in world rugby and I love it.
The worst or the best.
Or the best quite possibly.
I did enjoy seeing him twirl it in the little man's.
Never has a moustache suited a person quite as much.
He's got a volley now as it's a good scrum for VJ again and once more.
He's sore but this time just so hard to put down.
This time we'll bang it down the middle of the field.
Donaldson's back there in plenty of time sweeping across the trolling the backfield.
Ben Donaldson he's been very assured and all he's done so far in this entire World Cup and that's a great exit as well.
There's probably not been too much stress on the territorial game just yet but it's been a good one.
Australia play a little bit off the middle.
merely playing a little bit wider.
You can understand them all of a sudden a little bit of kicking and looking at Territory.
Neither team has given a quarter in this opening 20 minutes parity across the board.
Very few areas is what seems like a good throw to you bears of Britain's best available.
Point.
Exactly.
appeals away good tackle made on him by Porreki but Mataweisi is there to bring Fiji up over
halfway and get a penalty as well going against Fraser McRide losing his feet.
Just shows you if you play quickly from the line up there's that 10 meter space to run into the
camera on the corner very quickly did Fiji some good quick easy space made
and it's going to be another shot at goal for
him.
I'm very impressed by the discipline of Fiji you know coming out of the Wales game and they
they've just showed that they really work hard to try not to commit that and give away penalties
foolish penalties working really hard and on that occasion just getting one for themselves you know
it's it's good work that they do and good collective work from the forwards also the backs getting
involved great work at the breakdown and working working their socks off. Hold still please Australia.
This one now 45 odd on the angle Joel. Yeah the shot clock worries me it does take his time.
Intense focus again the distance is no problem nor is the direction it's superb kicking from
Simeone Coravalli to put Fiji in front of the second penalty six points to three.
Well that's a great strike under enormous pressure his team back against the walls
pressure on this young Scrum off it's a superb kick.
Fiji having now nudged just in front because it's brought down by Williami Matta.
Fiji fans singing here going around
this card of Gordon will stand firm underneath this one brings it down just the right side but
again it's just ragged all into the sideline. Well there's a there's a couple of issues around
a kick for possession if you place it near the touch line and it's well weighted you can get
the man to touch and win the line out perfect kick again. Australia Australia. It's had a good start to this game
Simeone Coravalli.
Step please on the line on the line come in Fiji.
Shortened line out for Fiji it's therefore Nassila Silla.
Oh Coravalli flicks it clever little ball back in field for Tangitangivalu.
Oh Coravalli.
Runners just ready to peel around the corner.
Good contest someone off. The referee is a good contest but Fiji maintaining possession.
Kui Sauver again
puncturing this Australian line Tangitangivalu once more his second carry in the movement he's
driven back in another good hit. Australia's defense has been very well organized so far
even though it might bend every so often.
Mataveisi tips it on for Tangitangivalu. Oh stolen away Australian hands play on is the call
put a hackless away downfield it's a huge trace for Randrata the bounces perfect for Australia.
It's a 53-22. Oh gone quickly have Australia here Sabu Karevi ball back in field for Nolonga Netawasi
they caught Fiji napping and Mark Nolonga Netawasi has struck for Australia.
Well they have a reputation for being the thinkers of world rugby Australia
they always come up with a way they make a plan boy have they made a plan this time around.
Great kick from Nick White got the 50-22 and then take it this is where the turnover came.
That's why you can get away with playing the ball on the ground like that.
Oh the kick was a great one though to be fair and Randrata was trying to get back there
the bounce is too good.
No happy knock on.
Yeah it's well taken and pretty much thought out just not sure that the
foundation on which it was bulk was right. And that last one going up there.
Mayatha Levy is still having words with the referee Andrew Brace
but it was heads-up play from Karevi and that man Nolonga Netawasi a rising star of world rugby
putting Australia in front.
Fiji hands. Okay it's not fun thank you.
Donaldson from wide and it will stay wide so the margin will be two.
Australia with the first try in the match eight points to six.
The sound of the crowd I think is enough said.
The crowd too seeing it on the big screen.
The points are on the board and Australia have some more this one down well as they
move forward to get it rolling nicely very close to that sideline though very close
and the ball spilled on Fiji's side here goes Kurovoli streaking away to the roar of the crowd
again up towards the 22 and then lost by Tangi down low.
Tangi's clearly over. A little rash of blood. Clearly over he's ran from there guys yeah.
Turnover ball so much space to run into maybe a little bit of excitement there for the big fella.
Okay left to the mark guys let's go. Great steal great turnover out it comes.
Quick to Australia. Kurovoli's advantage is over he's clearly run from there.
Fast feet stepping and going. Kumgon make the offload.
You can tell in a crowd of supporting every Frenchman in the stadium is wearing a white top today.
The roar you may have heard is from the crowd and I think the TMO has
come in to have another look at something. Hats the hit on Kurovoli as he went to ground.
First look.
You can also see that Kurovoli dipping down into the Nick White challenge and the tackle so you can
obviously understand and they're just giving a penalty which I think is the right decision.
Yeah I did right. Certainly no more than a penalty.
It's on the 15 net. He's such a wily contender isn't he the number nine for Fiji ducking and
diving. Such a difficult player to tackle where to tackle where to put your body because he's
just slithering around in between defenders and all of a sudden he dips and that's hence the reason
why it's just a penalty. Makes sense. I think the other element to this Fijian side is they just see
a bit of space and they just want to get into the space they just want to attack the gain line get
get over get going forward. Did it brilliantly on that time.
Yeah nice little touch from Nick White. I won't criticize his mustache again that's a real gentlemanly
touch. Kurovoli having won the penalty for his side with that darting run.
Chance to put his team back in front.
Absolutely superb off the tee once more.
Does just that and Fiji nuts your head as we head towards the half hour mark it's Fiji 9 Australia 8.
And use it. Kurovoli coming into the starting side for Frank Lomani who's on the bench.
Sends this one down Gordon is back there he's got good distance again though very good touch
finder once more from the halfback at the base. It's sensational what a great kick that is they've
made a lot of running meters as you can see but that is a superb kick. The line please. Under pressure
from the kickoff wanting to play downtown it's a great result.
Pereky nice quick ball off the top foot Frost Gordon.
Now through the hands they go Valentini who's stopped in his tracks on halfway.
The ball is there for the Wallabies to clear and it's the veteran front rower James Slipper who
crashes it up. Gordon he's got good footwork likes to take the ball to the line the fly half.
Shot down this time again Whiteseat sends it up into the air coming forward to bring it there's
a collision of Fiji embodies and it lands for Fraser McBride just a miscommunication by Fiji
and the kick dribbling dribbling dribbling Randradra there or to cover it.
But will he be forced to take the goal line drop out Australia putting some pressure on?
He won't mind that it's done well to get back there. The kick was a little clever one as well
trying to find a bit of space there down the blind side again Australia.
Thought he might have a little dot infield but covered.
All behind Fiji. Fiji ends up not enough talk I guess in the in the back three McBride is the
capitalised.
The drop out goes 50 odd meters on the fly is Fraser McBride
winds up rather it's Tom Hooper. Okay last feet. Winding up for Australia.
He's been asking questions of the Fiji defense down here but Thier
and now it is with McBride up to the 22. Fiji's defense solid will see it told to get out of there
so play on for Valentini.
Release now. There hasn't been a lot of room for Rob Valentini just yet. Gordon
from a standing start does really well Angus Bell he's good with ball and hand the loose head prop.
Maintaining position nicely as Noanganet Diwasi comes in for some close quarter work with his
great footwork and that's stolen by Fiji speaking of great brilliant work over the ball.
What a great job that Diwasi did.
He is a handful isn't he? Mark Noangit Diwasi. Strong over the ball clear left.
Just such fast feet steps gets away just defenders find it's find him so hard to bring to the ground.
When he did get to the ground yeah there was a quick release and a superb steal from Mbotiya.
Lovani Boccia of course playing for La Rochelle very familiar with French soil.
Two-time French European champions of course under Rune Nogara but what he does best plays
at the in the as a center but it can also play in the back row and here he is doing what he
does best ripping the ball getting down and making the turnover. It is unbelievable that he plays both
center and flanker that is Wasili Serevi what a legend he is. I had the privilege of playing with
him at the Leicester Tigers what a champion of a human being more and a great player. What a player
he was there were some shots in him riding the roller coaster of the game against Wales the
other day he'll be happy with this though as they rumble forward and earn an advantage here. Good
work from the line out for Fiji and here's the penalty could have only wanted to go instead the
option just to slow it down. Thanks guys number three collapsing the moor.
Well he's going to have a shot and accumulate points I hope to accumulate points we should say.
It's been a strong defensive effort from Australia you've got to say this
Kiwiside as much as they struggle to convert opportunities to points against Wales on the
weekend they've got a real they've had a fair bit of go forward this afternoon
once again Australia's defense have stood firm their forwards have been impressive defending the
malls and they've had the ball they've played tight around the fringes they've had a bit of
go forward it's been mainly the forwards carrying it up wherever you once or twice
that's really about what it's been.
And this pragmatic approach to try and take the points on offer when you've got a guy who
has banged them over from over the place here 52 meters the angle.
So
again it's perfect well that's his best strike of the lot
absolutely sweetly ruptures in the stands they're up a four RPG and all penalties
you expect them to be scoring tries they're kicking their goals and they're out to the lead.
12 points to eight Fiji lead
nicely taken down by Wayne Ngollo on that right wing side the Olympic gold medal is
coming into the team today as well.
Use it!
Area both teams have been very good exiting their own territory Gordon again as they come
flying down on him it'll have a crack back at them this time Carter Gordon has spied some space
before he gets cut in half by Soi Song with the ball spills free and that's picked up by
Sarikita Wetter and now Kurovoli trying to turn the Australians around sending it deep
holds gets a nice clearance away Jordan Pettaya well a nice clearance it's an outstanding clearance
good idea from Kurovoli but the kick may be not as good as it needed to be
there's probably a reason to smile after that kick Neil Hattley the
forward scratch he's worked a bit with England worked with Bath
Fiji long lead good job with the Australian forward so far
four another great of the game there world rugby women's player of the decade Jesse Tramuliet
standing French player looked thoroughly engrossed too didn't she
hold on this one just a little bobble from Kurovoli
there's Donaldson with him for the betty it's nice as this one's slightly off the side of the
boot and it's easily boredom by draw Ceci who gets around the oncoming Corobetti
makes his way up to halfway before he's ridden back by Valentini
there's no less heat in these tackles 35 minutes into the half flip fall out the back from Tangitangivalu
good hands down low from Matavese they're keeping the ball alive now holds all is that
Fiji again bored Naya Talevu this time though from a standing start
for Siriki Vataveta but playing advantage is referee Andrew Brace so
Tellett can have a little crack at the line here and find some space up the middle
advantage offside new advantage new advantage so Australia just creeping up offside as
Luke Pangifar is a wild ball and they will play this penalty
high tackle eight and offside here high tackle eight offside choice of penalties
just be within range of the kicker but not
oh this trouble for Australia is one of the problem in the second
Richie Wan was sat down yeah he's offside playing advantage for high tackle
a couple of minutes there of Fiji trying to keep the ball in hand again we saw
a little stage where both teams looked to just play it down so for a bit of territorial advantage
Fiji wanted to get it down there kick the goals because the kickers kicking brilliantly
it's a bit of a grind strain by the look of things the way they're stretching him out
oh his injury was just if he if he'd had any air would have fallen out with all the injuries of
Australia but
he was getting quite a cagey 30 odd minutes there's so much at stake for these teams both teams
that desire to attack but also the importance of the match overall to accumulate those points
and of course you can't help but think that if Fiji do win today and Australia going on
beat Wales it's going to come down to bonus points and points difference it's it's going
to be one of the pools where there's so much at stake in the last game or two to win five
tries and score lines and it's going to go to the wire now
Richie Arnold back in two position is a Wallaby World Cup winner
Joe Roth watches on all the greats in the house today oh he's looking a little concerned is Roffey
he'll be loving the back play though won't he there's some real outstanding wingers out there
today oh first line out goes astray from Fiji Australia Pinchas but they're going to get it
back are they getting locked in over that ball brilliant work to win it back
oh I was wondering about the decision here the secret steal
gets up brilliantly does the man who came in as a late replacement Nick Frost
well he didn't actually come in as a late replacement he came in late didn't he
good steal yeah of course it's Lavani Bhatia again he is just unstoppable
can't knock him off his feet the moment he goes down he's got those duck feet in that position
I mean you know they're pillars and he is digging and he'll win the pool every time
this is a brave call now leading by four just trying to twist the dagger a little bit you
guess three or four minutes to the halftime break haven't really had a ball down here in the real
red zone last line out with stolen and so is this one and it just stuck on the fingertips of
Hengis Bell coming back through it was Nick Frost again a couple of great interventions from the
big lock forward and that allows Carter Gordon to send it away danger not over
well if your second rise is stealing at line-up time you can kick it out
second one in a row that's just gone a little awry jumped in the front there frost okay Fiji
let's go up high it's a super steal at line-up time it's brave to send guys up that close to the line
and not stay on the ground and defend the mall but sometimes you reap the dividends
toys over gone into the front of this line out and again they go down the back for Williami
Matta it works this time and no it doesn't yes there was a knock on here just a little loss of
control and a couple of options for Fiji Buzia devastated
let's go fellas let's go with the thousand words every now and then
yeah just lost it as he went for the grab okay Fiji
let off for Australia to the back accidental let's go good pressure in the line out again though
left if there's one thing that Australia have actually got with frost and Richie Arnold two
really good line-up jumpers uh will skeleton obviously missing him in the mobile movement
department the bulldozing right through the middle and the bull carrying but in terms of
the line-ups Richie Arnold and frost absolutely clinical get really high in the air and they
work really well to try and steal their opponent's line-ups and both really tall two meters oh eight
Richie Arnold two meters a second six neck frost so opportunity lost for Fiji is stop Jordan Pitaia
sends us away to touch it's come off the side of the boot though there's very knowledgeable crowd
we're aware not quite what Jordan Pitaia would have wanted
I was looking at the line-up stats of Fiji earlier this morning seven about 30 percent to the front
about 30 percent to the middle and about 40 percent of their line-ups go to the back the
last one was to the back and it was successful except for the knock on the front is successful
and they go quick ball off the top this time the ball is dribbling along the ground but
the ball is dribbling along the ground but three sova hits and spins out of one and then
drags McRite with him another half a meter or so ball back in field for Landrada up to the 22
Fiji pressing play on is again draws says he puts a clever little quick kick across
he had it covered his way Nagorno bear down on him
and
just the odd ball going to ground now just as a result losing a little bit of momentum
every time when Roger gets his hands on the ball the crowd get you're not set properly excited
if the new ball is going to be set time go quickly it was a different ball that's why
play on well they weren't allowed to play on
Australia's fans take a breath
two meters two
Poreki hits his man isn't it White
second half underway in this pool sea match potentially decisive encounter of Fiji when
we'll blow the group wide open inside stop stop hold 40 minutes to decide that is
calming presence of Ben Donaldson at the back for Australia clears away
calm start to the second off after everything in the the first half that was pretty calm
decent clearance don't go in a simple Australia making sure they get away from that
to the danger zone
Fiji's line out had some troubles late in the half no such issue there though is
what he appeals off here runs straight into and then driven back by Valentini it's there though
as Fiji play forward and play early Wainegolo coming in and tried to slip the ball to
Rorcesi in traffic it comes free the mistake is made sometimes you just got to be a little
more patient than that don't use that very little chance so far today Wainegolo ran into the space
on the back of a really strong carry this is a brilliant tackle as well from Rob Valentini
drags him back no quick ball coming from there into the space he went just tried a
little impatient offload there might have been better off just hanging on
can understand the thinking though it's a game of opportunities right now oh he's playing the
price as well
guys guys we're waiting on your 14 anyway
oh
a handful of olympic gold medalists in this Fiji side
knows numbers are forming under pressure on big occasion
and you can understand the attention being paid to him as a winger you can't run unless
your ankle's 100 you can't step you can't do what's asked of you in terms of the basic
role of a of an outside back is he good does he stay in
and if juta wainegolo can't actually do that then it's not worth him being on the
pitch because he's electric isn't he he's such a wonderful player it looks like he's limping
and he's gonna it looks like he's going off which is a big blow for Fiji of course
an extraordinary athlete of course you talked about an olympic gold but what he does down at
for rugby club toulonet in the top cat top 14 is sensational wonderful player and it's a big shame
well you could just see his foot getting trapped under the tackler's body
as he went to ground that's what's done the damage he's making his way off
his tutor wainegolo he makes his way on played in the game against wales come on
um
who wainegolo replaced in the starting side so it's going to get more good minutes here
as australia that frost has been a real pillar in the middle once the fiji have got it and it's
sending this australian driving more backwards at the moment now it's controlled in the back though
and he's trying to add a couple more bodies in as australia are told to use it and frost will send
this up with that educated right box kick it's coming down for ramdra just on his own side a
halfway now wanganitawasi is there to wrap him up laid back for fiji
and use it
sets to return favorite kata gordon coming forward for australia they don't get near it
that wasn't allowed to bounce and it's got to land the toy
well every now and then you need a little bit of luck you need to bounce on the ball
you can send it right to a celly sir amy isn't that a wonderful picture
yeah well the kick was a good one straight in didn't get any hands on it it bounced between
the two jumpers who both dummy jumped two years over big and strong and powerful enough
pace to get to the corner try number one for fiji today and how important is that going to be
you can't shoulder the shoulders up sorry to carry on i was going to say you both jumpers
were almost doing dummy jumps they almost dummy themselves yeah you just can't leave the man
you know i mean it's over i mean he's already made eight ball carries 76 meters may tackle breaks
five you know and when he's on his own like that he will not stop him he's an absolute you know
locomotive fiji locomotive unstoppable take the ball and he's got a clear run to the line
no one is going to get near him that's what a try against wales off the bench was a real spark and
now he's extended fiji's lead here's kudovoli from the sideline
he cannot miss the new one he could have only had two more and fiji breakout early in the first
half 17 eight but he was more surprised than anyone was terry solver robbie all
bounced into his hands and he was gone yeah it's just too easy isn't it i mean you know
if he didn't fly like that he was exactly at a score point score tries uh you give him a free
run he's going to take it every time and importantly kudovoli just can't miss
there's something to to mention about uh sumi only kudovoli he's he's probably the third choice
number nine for fiji of course with caled muntz who of course uh you know picked up
that injury just going into the first game and then of course we have uh frank lomati on the bench
four charged down by richie arnold the big frame that can seize a penalty australia offside
at that breakdown of real for the luck for fiji ariel letoff he's a tall man richie arnold
not beyond the last man's feet is what's been ruled by andrew brace
tall and like that's going to charge down a few if he gets half a yard
you know that's an interesting point that is joel because um richie arnold doesn't just charge down
but he also you know with the driving balls he'll he'll get in get his hands in there well you know
swim as they call it and just get his hands on the ball on the player with the ball and bring them
down he is an absolute annoyance for every team that he comes up against line out
charge downs and in the in the uh in the defensive ball and this is a little worry
the kicker the man who's been on fire simi on the crew has got cramp to be cramping with
35 together he's a little bit of an issue okay are we good one two punch with lomati on the bench
the reason lomati not starting this one is that he just pulled up a little bit sore but fiji here
eventually at the least he's going to throw this but they are lining up an all new front
row to come on shortly stolen again by nick frost he has been a menace in the line out
the chance for australia to strike right back yeah oh we know
gordon just a little jink in a weave and then stopped by that man kudovol he can't keep the
scrum half out of it at the moment pitaya stands a low hard kick down it's
twisting and awkward for dross seseven it's going to go too long
simianna kurwan is stretching out those calves again he's probably short on a bit of game time
as well particularly in this humidity in this heat that we've experienced here in santatien
there's no advantage great steal at the line out again the ball is available frost up at the front
pops it down beautifully australia with a little free ball
gordon with a little step inside come off and then can the little grab before just too much on it
number nine what it gives a change at nine
such disappointment for simione kurwoli as frank lomati comes on to replace this outstanding half
first 46 minutes he had 14 points and you just can't underestimate how important those 14 points
are it's real confidence booster to fujimaru they've struggled to get over the white line
but he has put them in the game got them in front and he's controlled it for a fair chunk of this
this massive massive pull the side out
come on let's go
shoulder oh and nicely straight everybody
folks frank lomati vastly experienced now his 28th cap he's just pulled up a little sore after that
match against wales he's going to get a good 35 minutes here scrum is cribbing sideways a little
bit lomati is going to get a penalty at the back
of course fujimaru trying to do this for the last three or four scrums
trying to just put the pressure onto that ozzy front row particularly on the slipper side who's
playing outside in an unfamiliar position to him and in fact they got the wheel on the lucid side
which was quite impressive forced the penalty
number one stay square please you've got to stay square i think we've got to look at the start of
the second half the amount of possession that the australians haven't had as we see the the
penalties conceded nine to three which is uh very high for australia they just haven't managed to
get the ball in their hand and it's all been about fiji in the first seven minutes
this area has been an issue for fiji it's nicely brought down by
you saw narsila silla and what the vacie peels away all the ball just bounced hard into the
chest of lomati but they're playing under obama drapery had australia up offside
they've got a penalty here has fiji and they're all pointing all of them pointing to the post
penalty number 10 against australia
they were so disciplined against georgia australia and it will be a shot at goal
so
this is the game this road be world cup needed isn't it it's old fiji came unstuck a little
against wales lost a game they probably could have won probably think they should have won
backs against the wall they've come out here and they've been really good so far this afternoon
they've got a long way to go but if they just keep that scoreboard ticking over they're certainly on
the right track the french crowd wearing white shirts supporting the underdog
wonderful atmosphere it's it's just brilliant frank lomani just onto the field will take
over the goal kicking judy's from kudovoli two from two against wales last week
like
this one just pushed away to the left
just leaned back a little bit on it come on got a bit of a hook
so
fijian rugby league tass player makes his way on and it's gonna get the expense of
carter gordon which would be a little surprising it might need a reshuffle
very interesting change for eddie jones fly half coming off so they
will reshuffle ben donelson will go up into first five mark noangini toasi will
slot back to full back and huni walu on the wing
huni walu another of the handful of australian players with three changes
just said he sends this one higher noangini toasi underneath it
it's quite hard by it's timing perfect as the two 15s come together
five votes balatini just caught behind the game line so they could do better to really
well to get out of there and use it stay and again might all shake with the box kick and
send it for huni walu to chase van radder underneath it when he battle up in the air
and it's going to four foot maya talebu and fiji
van radder did just enough
barrels himself into the australian defense once more no more
lumani a real chase on this one for donelson had plenty of time
for noangini toasi to get it away and smash this way downfield keller eventually
receiving it on the five meter line fiji looking to open things up a little here for the world
ssc and it's not a bad clearance again from deep smart smart play realize the space was out on the
right hand side one long pass and then a good kick changes in the front row it's the front
row that have worked their socks off the softening in really hot conditions
maui matabezi and tongi make way and on come to vittar canavera penny rabai and masaki dongu
what a shift these three have put in
line out ball goes deep and down the back once more it's frost
karevi tries to get through his opposite stolen away by botia he tears off and there's one of the
new members sake donge straight into the action lumani for maya talebu let's see a maya talebu
the long lean center for fiji as they swing on to attack another of the fresh legs carries hard
and now straight up the middle lekema tangi tangi balu up over halfway
fiji pouring forward trying to find the same and then throwing that ball wide and over the sideline
again just as it looks to open up for them just keep it simple hands all it needed was simple hands
such a good opportunity creates it brilliantly there's the little steal what a turnover that is
is and he makes the little offload well bad news again james slipper getting a bit more attention
look at the numbers out wide are so well executed first wave of dummy runners ball in behind second
wave on fire four against one just needed simple hands just stay two and two at the front for me
straighten and hands more opportunities spurned
you know sometimes you just got to be a little bit more patient you know just uh you know attack
that line but just make sure that the defender comes as close as possibly can and then get it out
you know they they do it you know on their days off they do it all the time it is just a simple
pass that's all they needed to do i think that when we see a randrano what he what he did you
know with that final pass against wales um you know it's so disappointing they just got to be
a little bit more patient at times because that's when they'll make the difference
periccchi to frost it's been like a metronome that line out ball as valentini will crash it up to try
relieve some of this pressure that's been building on the wallabies and there's a nice open space
nice hole for angus belt look to get the arms free now australia trying to stretch and it's
a good ball for bonny valo up over halfway a sendering kick for himself to chase is going to be
far too heavy though it's a great breakout it may not have been the result australia wanted but
that's a great heart from this brilliant breakout space there was in behind a little chip over the
top the good hands were good just simple skills cover defense was coming oh and take that welcome
to the game yeah yeah
enough said
just the first glimpse of so the acid bunny harley such an electric ball player carry it runner
there wasn't too much space for him to run into that but it would have
would have been nice to see him have a little go and
robbie was talking about patience you know just maybe step inside try beat a man or two
set it up go through the phases again bull continuity
yeah i know some new front row for cg
bound to be a reset and there's a new front row on new personnel okay he's done well
early on in the game james slipper let's go guys let's go we talked about war horses in the game
134th cap playing on the side of the scrum where he is not as familiar with carrying an injury
by the sounds he's still going hard 54 minutes in james slipper
good shove this time from fiji it's gotten great front football from which to spread through the
hands of night the level stands a kid blowing hard into the ground for him more seated chase
voodoo is back there not a lot of room to move
what the advantage australia always advancing in front
i've got it here player offside from the cap number nine in front of the kicker
you know the house he's impressively impressive simon awaluy
yes he's one of the karma coaches we've seen sitting there
he's been given away too many penalties this afternoon only three that would have been the fourth
number nine franck lamani wearing the 21 shirt he was in front of the kick and carried on chasing
scrum i'll still tend to run that inside line but if you're in front you're in front
finding good important moment here for australia six don't change richie arnold they set the drive on
the big lock forward coming into the side late in the piece through the middle there
poor Ricky the captain plays the floor
australia all in tight at the moment karevi can't get through
what are you not many do frost just getting a little lateral and that allowed one at the level
and thank you to come through and now fegie are flowing through and
i'd stolen it but then lost it on the ground well he tried to pick it up inside the rock didn't he
should have should have just maybe stepped over and left it for the scrum off driven back by
the
okay
yeah no absolutely you know it's going to be important because isaac finds the lewis is going
to come on we've also got zane nongor is going to come on of course big back row of course from
queensland a couple of big changes here nick white will uh well just pass on a little bit of advice
and then make his way to the bench just next to me he needs to inject a little bit of speed into
the uh you know into the back line make that connection i think that's really important
and look at this man coming off he served he's done his job isn't he that's yes carriage galore
an old warhorse i think you called him ricky summed him up pretty well what a servant over
130 test matches only three starts outside said big ask of him today he's been wonderful
in tough conditions in a pack of forwards against the pack of forwards that have been really solid
uh big moment for isaac finds lilly wasa just his second cap he made his debut against france
okay well a month or so ago was uncapped at the time of this squad selection no take mcdermott
for australia today big ask of 27 year old halfback bit of a lake bloomer a huge opportunity as well
for this man there in 21
it's a very good platform this is for australia you know inside of the the fijian half let's see
exactly what they can produce from here they've got fast backs of course they need to get quick
ball or or just give the fijian scrum a little bit of a hassle here australia flood out to the
left putting numbers in for donaldson now playing up at fullback now donaldson
to run the show it's a good carry up over the 22 here's nongor with his first touch
this is good momentum here tipped on just as good a bet he sits down and mostly
still there for australia it's awkward the hands are outstanding down low
brilliant work from arnold good on betsy
australia it's a rare foray for them this close to the fiji line 10 meters short now as they line up
again the distribution is quick from finds lehli awasa five meters shorter the line pounding away
can't okay
well they've been so happy with the pull-up eddie jones and so disappointed in the scale
pull up on the board in front of the polls rory arnold is he the man with the carry and then
someone was just jacking in over that so quickly there's a little bit of a problem there for
for uh misaki donga he took a bit of a bang on the head i wouldn't be surprised if he just
called off for a hi a test that's definitely going to happen i think you know he was wobbly
he got up even bumped into a player as he tried to stack her back into position not in a good place
and botia yeah just uh suffering there on the grounds well he's been really good today
like 14 tackles you saw some unbelievable tackle statistics from the welsh against
fiji larsik botia turning it around today though that comes the hi it is going to be donga who
just goes off to get checked
so that brings luke tangi back on for misaki donga botia still down australia have made some
changes rob lehota out there in jersey 20 he's replaced fraser mick right looks like he's got
a bang in the jaw there more than anything else it's it's the left cheek the upper left cheek
but he's as hard as nails is that he's made of titanium for crying out loud he's back on the
pitch of course he's going to deal with this and did you see the size of that bicep while he was
on his orchards yes it's about the same size as joshua to asova's calf muscles you're right about
that skittles i think they are jordan orlessi also out there in jersey 16 for australia
replacement hooker thanks ricky you're calling the subs i appreciate it
oh that's who is here coming on
two and two it's fairly handy replacement isn't it
it is isn't it josey 20 here's fiji heading towards the final quarter of this match with
a 19-8 advantage over australia this one hanging in the air and bouncing kura betsy got nowhere
near it it's come off the hands of sangeetangeevalu and it will have been knocked on well that's at the
sky cams cable yeah very carefully it happened right in front of us hit the cable and deviated
and went the other way and i think that's got to be a fiji scrum
it's a bit of a debate going on down there now well they're just obviously
understanding who had possession from that but uh logically it should be fiji
okay let's go well i did knock it on when it did come down fiji so that's true australia
look like they're gonna get the put in
oh
that's one wheeling away in australia get the scrum penalty this time
okay
just trying to work around the outside there the fijians
same as the one over there number 17 right on the corner obviously gonna go and kick for the for
the corner here a little just um behind the halfway line and work that line out just like
they did before they've still got some very good jumpers in that line over richie anald there of
course and nick frost still in position it's working well just the mall they've got to get
some go forward now the line out it's not a problem fiji have defended them all pretty well though
dave parecki the captain's left the field so first throw for jordan ulessi
there it is for australia to floor richie anald once again fiji he would have given the disrupt
so ulessi has to come away with it over there to saraki daveta with a huge play for fiji
well the mall was coming backwards and there was a little peel to the
the left completely isolated but what a little jackal that is
game of i say it every week game of little mini battles look at this solo
ulessi around the corner and then hands on the ball
brilliant still the man born and raised in tiara on the east coast of new zealand the
community there did a fundraiser a big raffle to get his mum vicki here so vicki is in the crowd
just watching her boy steal that one away for fiji
well the kick goes out uh you can imagine what it's like back in fiji with all of the people
watching this encounter they must be on the edges of their seats uh all the fijians around the
world this is such a great position for them to be in up against australia of all of anaka to them
all as we head into the final 20 minutes and that one is a wobbly old line out it's getting tight
intense now mistakes coming into the game as it's tidied up by ulessi a chance for australia
through the on-field captain now korebi and now pitaya that's gone up over the shoulder
advantage being played for the high tackle
come off
just a captain please
captain
seatbelt tackle definitely a penalty it's on the shoulder
it is
first half penalties early on they'd only conceded a couple fijian that was for
very similar incidents so just a little warning well i said it earlier didn't i they do tackle
quite a they do make a point of tackling the ball of the jams it is a little risky at times
every now and then it slides up every now and then you end up with a seatbelt like that and
that's a penalty against them hold it up
looks like they've been to war the australian ford's here he is again nick frost in australia
will drive towards fiji's line it's stopped and stopped early and now cribbs sideways again
well lessy has it in the back for the wallabies going to have to use it now finds nearly awasa
will spread for korebi fiji getting it over this one again though another steal at the breakdown
well the momentum's been with australia for the last seven or eight minutes and you can just sense
the crowds under worry for this fijian team every time there's a steel made they're up there on
their feet the fijian fans the french fans shouting for the underdog and all of a sudden
hands on the ball steel again and a chance for relief 11 point game still 17 minutes it's just
everything to play for and just you could sorry really you could just you can just sense the
crowd starting to get concerned no joel is just saying joshua to so but what can't he do today
i mean you know he's been absolutely everywhere the carries the tackles uh scored a try he's been
absolutely everywhere such an important part of this fijian performance today now sila sila
in the middle this time for fiji okay stay slow this time for lamani and that's going to be a
penalty on and he's going to protest his case we can't do that to the
offback
it's a it's a free exit isn't it it's a marginal game it didn't sound like he was called for
offside it's sound like like he was called for attacking the man without the ball
and chiano came around just a little too quickly oh yeah he's not at his hands on the ball
so fiji who have been camped on their line for a good seven or eight minutes camped inside their
22 are out they're out of danger for now they've piggybacked them downfield has australia with
penalties now fiji go quick again a chance to really turn the screws here runs radra clatters
into the line now all night the lever ball down low his players knocked out everywhere
we're going to stop play here just an awkward collision of bodies
yeah they're taking him straight out into um you know to see the doctors back out
into the medical room it looks like for jordan well easy
just pulled that last kick of his a little just leaned back ever so slightly and got a bit of a
hook on it
so
lamani makes no mistake this time and now fiji starting to think it's possible is that a lead
is extended out 22 points to eight they lead australia 15 minutes to play oh and it's 14
points how important it's 14 points and the two promoter tries give you a draw
focaccia makes his way on yeah does it carevies come off okay he's been just outstanding as he
makes his way off surprised to see him though he's been one of the shining lights
so
the kickoff for fiji
out there in june 19 as well for fiji as well
on side on side use it
so
takes this one easily hasn't had a lot of open spaces but he's so dangerous the ball
spills into the hands of angus ballon this voracious defense of fiji comes forward at them
frost still going okay he's had a whale of a game the australian number four
gonna chance their arm now they kind of have to australia but thigh are stepping and jinking
and stopped again that one yeah no foul play carry on no foul play said the referee like it
crept up a little high again play on his throw a sissy safe his house is under that high ball
a little isolated and stolen though australia's turn for a big defensive play lalakai for kety
just onto the field
so
huge play from for kety to come onto the field and in that penalty
yeah good timing as well chasing the game 12 12 there's not a seat free here today at
joffroy kichard here in santa tian 41 294 fans here in this wonderful stadium that they call
the chaudron the cauldron well a little change they've also been in the wars joshua
who's been just outstanding this afternoon in a place barbara money got you to
getting in the applause and thoroughly deserves
come on
huge chance here for australia time starting to tick against them it's a good
line up for from now all the backs pile into this mall it's tucked in the back under the
right wing of wariki they've got advantage australia organized up towards the line
for reki another advantage for them
scores the try australia desperately needed
on the time it couldn't be better still got 10 or 12 minutes to go boy he's got some
little electrifying feet there to dot through the mall he's right in the french plays amongst the
forwards mixing it up stretches certainly scores
fiji battling to defend them all this time round and
penalty advantage was against them already the grounding was fine
they had to strike australia
quite as good this is an important kick as well
so
ben donaldson to close the gap for australia expertly done another two to the total
australia fighting back it's fiji 22 australia 15 would tend to play
coach hi from bonivalu the fact is that you know it all comes down now to the final 10 minutes and
every detail counts the small details will win this match discipline you know making sure that
you keep hold of the ball not giving away penalties free kicks or anything got to be
meticulous now restart lands in the hands of donaldson who pumps it back downfield again
fiji look to go quickly no quick kick from donaldson
onto the fijian 10 meter line good job should we should we should we say those dreaded words
what does it draw to do to this pool
australia certainly have the momentum right now
fiji the two best players have gone off in the last five or six minutes
can't find his target it's come off an australian hand they'll get a redo
you
do over from this time it's frost again with another steal
nick frost who's been in absolutely everything scooped up by tom hooper
australia it's almost the reverse of what we saw between fiji and wales where was
fiji flying home australia no but they're still chasing the game
sent high again i will see doesn't get to this one though knock on advantage for australia
why is elia wassup will recenter anything for valentini up the middle
gets through one can't quite but still going pumping those leads almost through a second
here's frost he skips out of a tackle up over the 22 australia piling forward
the gold jersey's attacking the fiji line nongor he's taken down in a good hit fiji have got
reorganized again flat ball for valentini on the angle well read
keep pressing away to the right where bonivalo is stationed no way through this time fiji hands on
ball another breakdown steal semi runs raja this time
first times they're left on the ball 11 oh the timing of the steals it's one thing to make the
steals the timing is so up and what's so important australia with so much momentum coming forward
they've been some huge performances valentini has been massive in carrying the ball frost has
been brilliant in the lineouts and in his work right and semi randran geier with a timely hands
on the ball a brilliant little bit of jackaling winning the penalty and some relief with seven
and a half minutes to go fiji hanging on by the fingertips at the moment really thought that
australia would uh you know just continue to go through the phases because they played a lot of
phases against georgia seven plus on average and still managed to score the points of course just
losing the ball at a critical time there big throw this one goes over the top and it's scooped up by
hooper the line up all sorts of shakes and wobbles from fiji australia spread koro betty he's gotten
the one in the toasi with him doesn't use him probably running out of room no one in the toasi
is koro betty rolls another meter and you can't roll like that on the ground australians off their
feet as well moments little moments should have let this go maybe straighten and make the pass
there was a player coming on the inside
process he could have shifted if he had made the pass so he carried it up
oh is that a shoulder charge
australian fans are thinking so
dave perickey's definitely asking the question as well
and passive reiwa louis glenn jackson next to him not doing quite so well
it's only maria will try and throw that in as quickly as possible
get the attention away from the shoulder charge
it's a massive shift from the tighthead
six minutes to go that line out much better from fiji and the mall is quick to set and rolling up
over halfway peeling off meters up what's the fijians now it's stopped for lamani and he's
going to clear
nervy ball out the back is teller has to go and scoop it up and he's swarmed upon by wallaby's
jerseys
lamani looking for some protection he's going to send this down koro betty
25 meters out from his own line brings it down safely and returns favorite three fijian players
back there and they're all going to run into each other lomani and draw sissy
no problem for lamani and again now i'm trying to find some open spaces looking for the 50 22
he only finds teller
now it's a good clearance for fiji australia will go quickly donaldson for petaiya
jordan patai looking for some spaces again it's straight down the throat of ran raja who picks
himself up off the floor and the game of forceback continues
all eating up the clock though as australia chase this game
who blinks first as fiji wind up again trying to get this in behind that australian back three
but once more koro betty is there so tired
it's
this one with a little more length but no problems once more finally
fiji go for the safety of the touch line on its bounce back and field in fact
the flag's gone up for a 50 22 has an australia's playing on
the assistant referee yuko piper has his flag up on the side
right
well was it 50 22 did it go out this side of the flag you think it may have gone out before
yeah it's out on the floor it's out on the floor which means
so it's not a 50 22 as much as the coaching staff think it may well have been
okay piper on the side had his flag out and down talking on but we carry on it's still there for
fiji
away
you'd imagine fiji are going to move very slowly to the scrum
contest for last time
okay let's go
time off let's go let's go let's go
oh
less than three minutes to play australia need a converter try just to tie us up
will fiji get their first win of this rugby world cup and their first over australia since 1954
oh
the scrum stands firm and then it screws and they're going to reset reset which all eats up time
oh fiji won't mind that they'll want that clock to wind down
time
side again coming around
you must stay down everybody stay down everybody time back on
oh
well it's not doom and gloom for australia they still got to play wales if they beat wales they
right back in the mix points well if it stays like this this group gets blown wide open
stable what do they get points difference bonus points are how will it be decided
here
fiji looking to put the final nail in
oh it's a great chase back but marika korevetti real pace because the break was sensational from
the captain number one now the calaver the timing of the pass was good on the outside
was ambassi trying to get those legs going korevetti got him from behind bonus points
saving quite possibly match saving if they can go and score from here
frost dragged another one down australia need to go 80 meters
is
donaldson sends it into touch one more throw there'd be some brilliant performances today
haven't that for australia rob valentini was superb nick frost was outstanding but that man
there made nine tackles two turnovers carried for 133 meters in 10 carries he has been absolutely
sensational just your two or so days our master card player in the match
fiji's lineouts found its form at just the right moment and now that's 30 seconds away from a
famous win and that gets their campaign rolling in france what's he to always lost control of that
knock on on the floor one more roll of the dice for australia ahead down to the wire
we called for a close game we called for an exciting game doesn't get much closer than
this australia will have one last throw of the dice here okay let's go from 60 meters out
scrum time under a little bit of pressure whole lot of new players on the field some fresh legs
so edge of the seats for us for the crowd for the viewers sensational game of rugby
at rugby world cup 2023 dosso fiji dosso echos around go fiji go those passionate fans but australia
one more chance the scrum disintegrates all over the place penalty fiji
hey
look what it means to these fijian players it's the first time since 1954 they have beaten australia